Mimansha Jha

mimansha1600@gmail.com | 7001274757 | Chennai, India

Summary

Innovative Web Development/UI-UX Student with experience in front-end and interface development, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP. Strengths include quick thinking and problem-solving skills. Detail-driven individual with the intention of exceeding expectations and improving project growth.

Education

Education	
SRM Institute Of Science and Technology	Sep 2022 – Present
B.Tech \cdot Computer Science with Business Systems \cdot Chennai	8.97
North Point Senior Secondary School	Apr 2021 – Jun 2022
12th · CBSE · Kolkata	379/500
The Cambridge School	Apr 2019 - Mar 2020
10th · IGCSE · Kolkata	559/700
Experience	
Bharat Intern Welcome Letter	May 2023 – Jun 2023

Google For Developers | Certificate

Android Developer Virtual Internship · Intern · Learning

Web Development · Intern · Virtual Internship Program

Online

Apr 2023 – Jun 2023 Online

Projects

Sports League Management

Python, OOP, MySQL SQL

Mini Project – utilized Python for data structures, OOP, file handling, and automation, and MySQL for database design, querying, and data management in the Sports League Management project.

Dual Axis Solar tracker

- Arduino Semi-Conductor

'Best Working Model' at TechKnow Contest – utilized skills in microcontroller programming, sensor integration, motor control, and circuit design to optimize solar panel orientation for maximum energy efficiency.

Self Tracking Line Car

Motor Driver Circuit Microcontroller Programming

Applied skills in microcontroller programming, sensor integration, motor control, real-time processing, and circuit design to create autonomous line-following vehicles.

Integrating Sustainability into Corporate Strategy: A Path to Long-Term Sep 2024 - Present Competitive Advantage

Dr. Nagalakshmi M.V.N. (Corresponding author) · Management & Implementation Business Strategy

Portfolio
CSS, JS
Un 2024 – Present
Web Development

Certifications

Introduction to Data Analytics course | Certificate

Dec 2024 -

AWS Machine Learning Foundations Course \mid Certificate

AWS

Networking Basics | Badge Oct 2024 -

CISCO

Volunteering

Raynagar Free Primary School Volunteer · Community Connect

May 2024 - Jun 2024

Feb 2024 -

Competitions

French Word Power

First · Quebec Government Office, Mumbai

Concours Romain Rolland

Finalist · Alliance Française de Normandie, France

Techknow Contest Feb 2023

Winner · SRM Department of Nanotechnology

Conferences and Workshops

Activation Workshop on Metaverse and Extended Reality

AICTE

Design and Develop Workshop for UI/UX

Google Developer Student Clubs · SRM

Extra Curricular Activities

SRM MUN Society Oct 2023 – Aug 2024

Next Gen AI Oct 2024 -

Skills

Python, C/C++, HTML/CSS, Java, SQL, UI/UX

Languages

English [Professional Working Proficiency], Hindi [Native Proficiency], Bengali [Limited Working Proficiency], French [Elementary Proficiency], German [Fundamental Proficiency]

Links

LinkedIn, GitHub